var data = [
    {
        question: "In genetic algorithm, in the mutation process ______",
        options: ["sequence is not changed","sequence is changed","gaps are not rearranged","gaps are not inserted"],
        correct_option: "sequence is not changed"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not among the methods for finding localized sequence similarity?",
        options: ["Extraction of blocks from a global or local MSA","Pattern blocking","Block analysis","Profile analysis"],
        correct_option: "Pattern blocking"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue regarding the Chou-Fasman and GOR methods?",
        options: ["They suffer from the fact that the prediction rules are somewhat arbitrary","They are based on single sequence statistics with clear relation to known protein-folding theories","They are developed in the 1970s","Both are the first-generation methods"],
        correct_option: "They are based on single sequence statistics with clear relation to known protein-folding theories"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue about homology modelling?",
        options: ["It doesn't involve the evolutionary distances anywhere","The principle behind it is that if 2 proteins share a high enough sequence similarity, they are likely to have very similar 3-dimensional structures","Homology modelling predicts protein structures based on sequence homology with known structures","It is also known as comparative modelling"],
        correct_option: "It doesn't involve the evolutionary distances anywhere"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue about loop modelling step? ",
        options: ["The gaps cannot be directly modeled","Loop modelling is required for closing the gaps","in the sequence alignment for modelling, there are not regions producing gaps in sequence alignment","In the sequence alignment for modelling, there are often regions caused by insertions and deletions producing gaps in sequence alignment"],
        correct_option: "in the sequence alignment for modelling, there are not regions producing gaps in sequence alignment"
    },
    {
        question: "There are various electronic gates like OR, AND, NOR, XOR etc. Which gate is described as universal?",
        options: ["OR","AND","XOR","NOR"],
        correct_option: "NOR"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following does not describe local alignment algorithm?",
        options: ["In traceback step, beginning is with the highest score, it ends when 0 is encountered","First row and first column are set to 0 in initialization step","Score can be negative","Negative score is set to 0"],
        correct_option: "Score can be negative"
    },
    {
        question: "The complexity of Bubble sort algorithm is",
        options: ["O(n)","O(log n)","O(n2)","O(n log n)"],
        correct_option: "O(n2)"
    },
    {
        question: "The worst case complexity for insertion sort is",
        options: ["O(n)","O(log n)","O(n2)","O(n log n)"],
        correct_option: "O(n2)"
    },
    {
        question: "The complexity of Binary search algorithm is",
        options: ["O(n)","O(log )","O(n2)","O(n log n)"],
        correct_option: "O(log )"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Data Structure is mainly used for implementing the recursive algorithm?",
        options: ["Queue","Stack","Linked list","Tree"],
        correct_option: "Stack"
    },
    {
        question: "What’s happen if base condition is not defined in recursion ?",
        options: ["Stack underflow","Stack overflow","None of these","Both a and b"],
        correct_option: "Stack overflow"
    },
    {
        question: "In recursion the condition after which the function will stop calling itself is",
        options: ["Base condition","Function call","Both","None"],
        correct_option: "Base condition"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following information is stored in a doubly-linked list’s nodes?",
        options: ["Value of node","Address of next node","Address of the previous node","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following are applications of linked lists?",
        options: ["Implementing file systems","Chaining in hash tables","Binary trees implementation","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "An algorithm is _____",
        options: ["A procedure for solving a problem","A problem","A real-life mathematical problem","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "A procedure for solving a problem"
    },
    {
        question: "An algorithm which uses the past resuts and uses them to find the new results is _____",
        options: ["Brute force","Divide and Conquer","Dynamic programming algorithms","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Dynamic programming algorithms"
    },
    {
        question: "A complexity of algorithm depends upon ____",
        options: ["Time only","Space only","Both time and space","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Both time and space"
    },
    {
        question: "For a recursive algorithm ______",
        options: ["a base case is necessary and is solved without recursion","a base case is not necessary","does not solve a base case directly","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "a base case is not necessary"
    },
    {
        question: "Optimization of algorithm means _______",
        options: ["making that algorithm fast by time and compact by space","making that algorithm slow by time and large by space","making that algorithm fast by time and large by space","making that algorithm slow by time and compact by space"],
        correct_option: "making that algorithm fast by time and compact by space"
    },
    {
        question: "For an algorithm which is the most important characteristic that makes it acceptable _______",
        options: ["Fast","Compact","Correctness and Precision","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Correctness and Precision"
    },
    {
        question: "An algorithm can be represented through _____",
        options: ["flow charts","pseudo-codes","instructions in common language","all of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "all of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following case does not exist in complexity theory?",
        options: ["Best case","Worst case","Average case","Null case"],
        correct_option: "Null case"
    },
    {
        question: "The complexity of Fibonacci series is _______",
        options: ["O(2n)","O(log n)","O(n2)","O(n log n)"],
        correct_option: "O(2n)"
    },
    {
        question: "Indicate constant time complexity in terms of Big-O notation.",
        options: ["O(n)","O(1)","O(log n)","O(n^2)"],
        correct_option: "O(1)"
    },
    {
        question: "Find the slowest time complexity",
        options: ["O(n)","O(n^2)","O(n!)","O(2^n)"],
        correct_option: "O(n!)"
    },
    {
        question: "Dijkstra’s algorithm is used to solve __________  problems?",
        options: ["Network lock","Single source shortest path","All pair shortest path","Sorting"],
        correct_option: "Single source shortest path"
    },
    {
        question: "The Bellmann Ford algorithm returns _____ value?",
        options: ["String","Boolean","Double","Integer"],
        correct_option: "Boolean"
    },
    {
        question: "Representation of data structure in memory is known as?",
        options: ["Storage structure","File structure","Recursive","Abstract Data Type"],
        correct_option: "Abstract Data Type"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following sorting algorithms provide the best time complexity in the worst-case \n scenario?",
        options: ["merge sort","quick sort","bubble sort","selection sort"],
        correct_option: "merge sort"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following data structure is used to perform recursion?",
        options: ["Linked list","Array","Queue","Stack"],
        correct_option: "Queue"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a Divide and Conquer algorithm?",
        options: ["bubble sort","selection sort","heap sort","merge sort"],
        correct_option: "merge sort"
    },
    {
        question: "Hamiltonian path problem is _________?",
        options: ["NP problem","P class problem","NP-complete problem","N class problem"],
        correct_option: "NP-complete problem"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the technique called in which it does not require extra memory for carrying out the \n sorting procedure?",
        options: ["Stable","Unstable","In-place","In-partition"],
        correct_option: "In-place"
    },
    {
        question: "Depth First Search is equivalent to which of the traversal in the Binary Trees?",
        options: ["Pre-order Traversal","Post-order Traversal","Level-order Traversal","In-order Traversal"],
        correct_option: "Pre-order Traversal"
    },
    {
        question: "The Data structure used in standard implementation of Breadth First Search is?",
        options: ["Stack","Queue","Linked list","Tree"],
        correct_option: "Stack"
    },
    {
        question: "The Depth First Search traversal of a graph will result into?",
        options: ["Linked List","Tree","Graph with back edges","Array"],
        correct_option: "Tree"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not an application of Depth First Search?",
        options: ["For generating topological sort of a graph","For generating Strongly Connected Components of a directed graph","Detecting cycles in the graph","Peer to Peer Networks"],
        correct_option: "Peer to Peer Networks"
    },
    {
        question: "When the Depth First Search of a graph is unique?",
        options: ["When the graph is a Binary Tree","When the graph is a Linked List","When the graph is a n-ary Tree","When the graph is a ternary Tree"],
        correct_option: "When the graph is a Linked List"
    },
    {
        question: "In Depth First Search, how many times a node is visited?",
        options: ["Once","Twice","Equivalent to number of indegree of the node","Thrice"],
        correct_option: "Equivalent to number of indegree of the node"
    },
    {
        question: "Breadth First Search is equivalent to which of the traversal in the Binary Trees?",
        options: ["Pre-order Traversal","Post-order Traversal","Level-order Traversal","In-order Traversal"],
        correct_option: "Level-order Traversal"
    },
    {
        question: "The Data structure used in standard implementation of Breadth First Search is?",
        options: ["Stack","Queue","Linked list","Tree"],
        correct_option: "Queue"
    },
    {
        question: "A person wants to visit some places. He starts from a vertex and then wants to visit every place \n connected to this vertex and so on. What algorithm he should use?",
        options: ["Depth First Search","Breadth First Search","Trim’s algorithm","Kruskal’s algorithm"],
        correct_option: "Breadth First Search"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not an application of Breadth First Search?",
        options: ["Finding shortest path between two nodes","Finding bipartiteness of a graph","GPS navigation system","Path Finding"],
        correct_option: "Path Finding"
    },
    {
        question: "In preorder traversal of a binary tree the second step is __________",
        options: ["traverse the right subtree","traverse the left subtree","traverse right subtree and visit the root","visit the root"],
        correct_option: "traverse the left subtree"
    },
    {
        question: "An important application of binary tree is ______",
        options: ["Huffman coding","stack implementation","queue implementation","traverse a cyclic graph"],
        correct_option: "Huffman coding"
    },
    {
        question: "A randomized algorithm uses random bits as input inorder to achieve a _____________ good \n performance over all possible choice of random bits.",
        options: ["worst case","best case","average case","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "average case"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following are probalistic algorithms?",
        options: ["Las Vegas Algorithm","Monte Carlo Algorithm","Atlantic City Algorithm","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "Prisonner’s dilemma can be related to the following:",
        options: ["cooperative behaviour","graph theory","all of the mentioned","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "cooperative behaviour"
    },
    {
        question: "Unix sort command uses _________ as its sorting technique.",
        options: ["Quick Sort","Bucket Sort ","Radiz Sort","Merge Sort"],
        correct_option: "Quick Sort"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following can be referred to as applications of Randomized algorithm?",
        options: ["Quicksort","Min Cut","Verifying Matrix Multiplication","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following statements for a simple graph is correct?",
        options: ["Every path is a trail","Every trail is a path","Every trail is a path as well as every path is a trail","Path and trail have no relation"],
        correct_option: "Every path is a trail"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the number of edges present in a complete graph having n vertices?",
        options: ["(n*(n+1))/2","(n*(n-1))/2","n","Information given is insufficient"],
        correct_option: "(n*(n-1))/2"
    },
    {
        question: "A connected planar graph having 6 vertices, 7 edges contains _____________ regions.",
        options: ["15","3","1","11"],
        correct_option: "3"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following properties does a simple graph not hold?",
        options: ["Must be connected","Must be unweighted","Must have no loops or multiple edges","Must have no multiple edges"],
        correct_option: "Must be connected"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is true?",
        options: ["A graph may contain no edges and many vertices","A graph may contain many edges and no vertices","A graph may contain no edges and no vertices","A graph may contain no vertices and many edges"],
        correct_option: "A graph may contain many edges and no vertices"
    },
    {
        question: "A graph with all vertices having equal degree is known as a __________",
        options: ["Multi Graph","Regular Graph","Simple Graph","Complete Graph"],
        correct_option: "Regular Graph"
    }
    
]
export default data;